Ayush Bisht

Uttarakhand, India



bisht.ayush2001@gmail.com



7037296166



linkedin.com/in/ayush-bisht-9a5582192

Summary

Hey, my name is Ayush Bisht, a self-taught passionate Full stack developer from India, based in Uttarakhand with proven technical, organizational, and communication skills, working with Agile and designing software solutions. Offering strong React skills and working experience with SQL, Python, Django, JavaScript frameworks, and many more.

Experience

- Full Stack Developer

NamaSYS

Sep 2021 - Nov 2021 (3 months)

- * Carried out the Machine Learning-based web application development using modern JavaScript frameworks and libraries including React, SAAS, and MUI.
- * Redesigned the complete UI of the application for version 2.0 and also Integrate Rest APIs for engine status, model building, model guery, PayPal, and stripe payment gateway endpoints at the frontend.
- * Collaborated in an agile manner with cross-functional team sprints, and participated in 100% of daily scrums, and also carried out weekly feedback sessions on the product design and progress report with international clients.

Python Developer

NamaSYS

Jul 2021 - Sep 2021 (3 months)

- * Work on SACRD, a web application for Multi-GAAP Financial Reporting Automation.
- * Perform Benchmark analysis of the product to optimize the application's productivity and performance.
- * Eliminate the dead and redundant code from the application and automate the code standardization testing using a pre-commit library for both frontend and backend.

Full Stack Developer

Shree Balajee Filling Station

May 2021 - Jul 2021 (3 months)

https://www.shreebalajeefillingstation.com/

Education



🥨 Bipin Tripathi Kumaon Institute Of Technology

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science Aug 2019 - Sep 2023



Shri Guru Ram Rai Public School - India

Intermediate, Science Jan 2018 - Apr 2019

Licenses & Certifications

Description Learn Python Programming Masterclass - Udemy

UC-12b74f50-feaa-4fb7-9d72-eb99cd0afb20

Mastering Data Structures & Algorithms using C and C++ - Udemy UC-90e023f2-fee2-489a-a408-754f5b562dc1

Getting Started with AWS Machine Learning - Coursera 5d9eadf2121586035b3de90d950eca47

IEEE Xtreme Coding Competition 14.0 (AIR - 30) - IEEEXtreme mW09w27SQ1jFpZ

Skills

Responsive Web Design • Agile Methodologies • User Experience (UX) • REST APIs • Django • Redux.js • AJAX • Programming • Python (Programming Language) • C (Programming Language)

Honors & Awards

Top Performer in Computer Science - Shri Guru Ram Rai Public School, Kotdwara Feb 2019

Nominated as the best performer in Computer Science 2018-2019 at intermediate.